<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "CloudStack_Quick_Install_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-CloudStack_Quick_Install_Guide-VMware_vsphere_installation">
	<title>VMware vSphere Installation and Configuration</title>
	<para>VMware vSphere  must be installed on the Hosts. VMware vSphere can be downloaded and purchased from the VMware Website 
	(<ulink url=https://www.vmware.com/tryvmware/index.php?p=vmware-vsphere&lp=1>https://www.vmware.com/tryvmware/index.php?p=vmware-vsphere&lp=1</ulink>) 
	and installed by following the VMware vSphere Installation Guide. 
	</para>
	<para><application>VMware vCenter Standard Edition 4.1</application> must be installed and available to manage the vSphere Hosts.</para>
	<important><para>You must re-install VMware ESXi if you are going to re-use a host from a previous install. </para></important>
	<important><para>The CloudStack requires VMware vSphere 4.1.  VMware vSphere 4.0 is not supported.</para></important>
	<important><para>All hosts must be 64-bit and must support HVM (Intel-VT or AMD-V enabled). All Hosts within a Cluster must be homogenous. That means the CPUs must be of the same type, count, and feature flags.</para></important>
	<important><para>CloudStack requires ESXi.  ESX is not supported.</para></important>
	<para>The following sections contain information about configuring the VMware vSphere.</para>
	<section id="sect-vmware-licensing">
		<title>Licensing</title>
		<para>The CloudStack require vSphere and vCenter, both version 4.1. vSphere Standard is recommended.  
		Note however that customers need to consider the CPU constraints in place with vSphere licensing.  See 
		<ulink url="http://www.vmware.com/files/pdf/vsphere_pricing.pdf">http://www.vmware.com/files/pdf/vsphere_pricing.pdf</ulink>
		 and discuss with your VMware sales representative.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="vmware-esxi-host-setup">
		<title>ESXi host setup</title>
		<para>All ESXi hosts should enable CPU hardware virtualization support in BIOS. 
		Please note hardware virtualization support is not enabled by default on most servers. 
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="vmware-phys-host-setup">
		<title>Physical host setup</title>
		<para>You should have a plan for cabling the vSphere hosts. Proper network configuration is required 
		before adding a vSphere Host to the CloudStack. To configure an ESXi host, you can use vClient to add 
		it as standalone host to vCenter first.  Once you see the host appearing in the vCenter inventory tree, 
		click the host node in the inventory tree, and navigate to the Configuration tab:</para>
		<inlinemediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="images/vmware-network-1.png" format="PNG" />
                        </imageobject>
                </inlinemediaobject>
		<para>In the host configuration tab, click the “Hardware/Networking” link to bring up the networking configuration page as above.</para>
		<section id="vmware-phys-host-setup-config-switch">
			<title>Configure vSwitch</title>
			<para>A default virtual switch vSwitch0 is created.   CloudStack requires all ESXi hosts in the cloud to use 
			the same set of virtual switch names. If you change the default virtual switch name you will need to configure 
			one or more CloudStack configuration variables as well.  This document will not delve into that situation, but it is
			covered with more detail in the Installation Guide
			</para>
		</section>
		<section id="vmware-phys-host-increase-ports">
			<title>Increase number of switch ports</title>
			<para>By default a virtual switch on ESXi hosts is created with 56 ports.  We recommend setting it to 
			4096, the maximum number of ports allowed. To do that, click the “Properties…” link for virtual switch 
			(note this is not the Properties link for Networking.)
			</para>
			<inlinemediaobject>
	                        <imageobject>
        	                        <imagedata fileref="images/vmware-network-2.png" format="PNG" />
                	        </imageobject>
	                </inlinemediaobject>
			<para>In vSwitch properties dialog, select the vSwitch and click Edit button, you should see the following dialog:</para>
                        <inlinemediaobject>
                                <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="images/vmware-network-3.png" format="PNG" />
                                </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject>
			<para>You can change the number of switch ports in above dialog, after you’ve done that, 
			ESXi hosts are required to reboot in order for the setting to take effect.
			</para>
		</section>
		<section id="vmware-phys-host-setup-config-vcenter-mgmt-network">
			<title>Configure vCenter Management Network</title>
			<para>In the vSwitch properties dialog box, you may see a vCenter management network.  
			CloudStack also requires vMotion to be configured properly, select the management network 
			item in the dialog, click edit button</para>
                        <inlinemediaobject>
                                <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="images/vmware-network-4.png" format="PNG" />
                                </imageobject>
                        </inlinemediaobject>
			<para>Ensure vMotion and Management traffic options are enabled.</para>
			
		</section>
		
	</section>
	<section id="vmware-addhosts">
		<title>Add Hosts</title>
		<para>Host management for vSphere is done through a combination of vCenter and the CloudStack admin UI.  
		As an administrator you must decide if you would like to use clusters or standalone hosts.  This document only
		covers the usage of standalone hosts. See the Installation Guide for more details. 
		</para>
		<important><para>The vCenter user that is provided to the CloudStack should have full administrator privileges.</para></important>
		<para>Use vCenter to add standalone nodes into vCenter management.   You will later add these nodes into the CloudStack one at a time.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
